# Sebastian Heucke

**Molecular Biologist** 

## Sebastian Heucke

**Bahnhofstraße 30a** Grafing 85567

sebastianheucke@gmail.com



## **Skills**

Molecular biology and genetics through my studies at university.

Bioinformatics and NGS Knowledge from work experience and courses.

Programming languages: bash, python and R through courses and self education.

Data science and machine learning: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Sklearn, Pytorch, Jupyter notebooks, Colab notebooks through worked on projects

Building Web applications: Django, Html, Css, Heroku for easier availability and usage of results.

# **Experience**

## **Institute of Pathology** / Scientist

2015 - PRESENT, LMU Munich

#### 2017-2020

- Development of small Web Applications with Python using Web Framework Django, Html, Css and Plotly
- Building up Machine Learning Knowledge
- Data science projects on clinical data
- Establishment of RNASeq wet lab and setting up a pipeline using bash scripts and python
- Data analysis of RNASeq using Galaxy workflows
- RNASeq analysis using R in Jupyter notebooks

## 2016-2017

- Establishment of new NGS panels
- Illumina: NextSeq 500
- Data analysis of NGS results
- Linux/Bash Scripting
- Development of tools using python

#### 2015

- Wetlab NGS on platforms Ion Torrent: Chef, PGM, S5 Prime
- Process optimization NGS Panels for diagnostic routine
- Pyrosequencing technology
- Programming of tools for automation of NGS-workflows with VBA in Excel
- Library preparation and sequencing for clinical studies

## **Education**

## TH Karlsruhe / Master Biologie

October 1996 - June 2003, Karlsruhe